# **ALVIS ZHENG**

Shanghai, China ◆ C: +8618516751248 ◆ alvis\_zheng@apple.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Rich experience in business processes and controls. Strong ability to recognize complex problems related to functional objectives, analyzing situations and implementing solutions. Highly independent and able to ramp quickly in a new environment. Strong ability to build rapport with internal and external partners. Abundant experience in Shared Services, process transitions, recruiting and people management.

WORK HISTORY

#### O2C SME, 12/2015

# Apple Computer Trading (Shanghai) Co.,Ltd.

- Global perspective combined with deep local knowledge
- Co-leader of site-wise continuous improvement program (Infinite Innovation) to build the governance framework
- Actively participate in various types of projects including Retail Expansion, iRecon, Retail/Online payment
- Strong Finance Shared Service background
- Close partnership with global team (IS&T, GFP, GPO) based in Austin and Cupertino
- Represent O2C team throughout the Project Life Cycle
- Understand as-is process and develop to-be process and system requirements
- Coordinate UAT, resource planning, cutover and recommend alternative solutions
- Support ad-hoc requests and changes affecting O2C team as needed basis
- Liaise with the O2C teams, IS&T, GPO, GFP team on O2C relevant process area discussions
- Partner with business team to identify process improvement initiatives and areas
- Arrange regular project reviews with O2C stakeholders and report project status
- Identify risks associated with projects

## Purchase to Pay Manager- North Asia, 11/2012 to 11/2015

#### **Texas Instruments**

- Managed ongoing daily operations and escalations
- Process coverage including Accounts Payable, Travel and Entertainment and Purchasing Coordination
- Oversaw in-scope region including China, Hong Kong, Taiwan, Korea

- Established China P2P team and developed strategic planning for Geo Expansion
- Managed key process metrics
- Led process standardization initiatives
- Coached new employees and provided career counseling
- Recruited, developed and retained talent

# Accounts Payable Operation Manager, 09/2010 to 11/2012

## Bayer

- Managed ongoing daily operations and escalations
- Monitored actual cost vs. forecast for department expenses
- Managed Geo Expansion related project activities and transitions
- Led process standardization and drove continuous improvement
- Recruited, developed and retained talent

### Service Delivery Manager, 04/2006 to 09/2010

#### Accenture

- Managed ongoing daily operations and escalations
- Led various finance and accounting projects in O2C/P2P area
- Drove and monitored knowledge transfer of key processes
- Executed to service level agreement and related metrics
- Identified and implemented process improvement initiatives
- Managed, counseled and coached process leads
- Recruited, developed and retained talent

### Call Center Agent, 01/2005 to 04/2006

#### Lufthansa

- Performed direct sales, facilitated general inquires, offering membership services
- Coached new colleagues as part of on-job training

EDUCATION	
EDUCATION	

**Bachelor of Arts**: Business Information Technology, 2004

Coventry University, UK - Completed in Inti College Malaysia